Martez Howard

SUMMARY

To give you a brief overview of my skill set – For over five years I have been working in both DevOps / Cloud and software engineering obtaining various roles contributing to a multitude of projects. I specialize in cloud infrastructure creation and maintenance. I focused my career on setting and syncing up across distributed systems in which the user can access the clients cloud architecture. My knowledge and skill set are focused on DevOps / Cloud including highly used tools in development such as Docker and Kubernetes for containerization, scalability, and load balancing.

EXPERIENCE

Icosa Studios, LLC - DevOps / Cloud Engineer

May 2022 - Current

I am currently providing services to Icosa Studios. Majority of the tasks involve adding new features onto various AWS hosted systems. Features include debugging cloud infrastructure, internet gateways, RDS clusters, EKS configurations, Elastic Beanstalk deployments, and CloudWatch monitoring.

- Test and build VPC, in High Availability mode, and connect to RDS instances through networking and security groups
- Setup Docker and Kubernetes containerization for both local development and production
- Share input on infrastructure best practices and implementations

Endpoint Closing, Inc - DevOps Engineer

September 2019 - May 2020

Developing at Endpoint Closing I maintained their product website and mobile application.

- Test and deploy code changes through CI/CD pipeline to staging and production environment
- Maintain Docker containers for local development
- Troubleshooting deployments to the CI/CD pipeline

Presence Product Group, LLC - Full Stack Engineer

March 2018 – October 2019

Developing and consulting at Presence in San Francisco on highprofile consumer-facing applications. Many of the projects were built using React on the front end and Nodejs, PHP, or Python on the back end using Docker containers and CircleCi for integration.

- Test and build both front end and backend infrastructure
- Share thoughts and ideas with the team
- Test and build components for consumer experience

Gigs4martez@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/martez-howard-b38038108

GitHub

https://github.com/dizthewize

KEY SKILLS

Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform,
Ansible, Prometheus, Jenkins, linux,
Powershell, unix, Git / Github, AWS (
EKS, ECR, Elastic Beanstalk, S3, RDS,
CloudWatch, EC2, VPC, Route53,
CloudFront), Azure, Scripting,
postgresSQL, MySql, NoSql, Sql,
MongoDB, Python, NodeJs, GraphQL,
Typescript, React, React Native,
Redux

EDUCATION

American River College
Business Admin. Marketing

CSU - Sacramento

Business Admin. Marketing